hey guys you got to watch this video
this guy hits a home run and then throws
the bat
up and it stays up for really long
time I got a timer going right
here and it stays up for 11.83 seconds
so let's figure out how high did the bat
reach we can visualize the path of the
bat as a prao where the horizontal axis
can be t for time in seconds and the
vertical axis can be H for the height
that the bat goes so we're interested in
this point right here how high did the
bat reach so this is the formula we're
going to use the height is equal to -4.9
T ^2 plus the initial velocity time time
plus the initial height so we'll call
the initial height zero because the top
of the bat is really close to the ground
as he throws it and we don't know the
initial velocity but we do know at the
time 11.83 seconds the height once again
was zero so we can use this information
to find the initial velocity let's copy
down our equation let's give our our El
some space let's plug in zero and in the
place of these T's let's plug in 11.83
and in the place of the H let's plug in
zero 4.9 * 11.83 2 is-
68575 and let's copy down everything
else let's add 68575 to both sides we
end up with 68575 is equal to 11.83 *
the initial velocity after we divide
both sides by 11.83 we get the initial
velocity is
57.97 and that's measured in meters per
second and if you're curious that's
about
28.6n km/ hour or 129. 68 mph so that's
pretty fast we can update the initial
velocity up here to
57.97 and now we don't need this stuff
anymore now that we know our initial
velocity here's our new equation
representing the height so now to find
this maximum height we first need to
plug in this point right here which we
know is
11.83 the axis of symmetry will go
through that maximum point we can find
this Axis of Symmetry by taking the aage
aage of these two x intercepts and
that's going to give us
5915 and so now we take our equation
again plug in 5915 for T and we get our
height of 171.5 M and that is the answer
to our question how exciting